Chris Campbell

Software Engineer

Mexico City | +1 (248)877-0395 | christopherecampbell@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I'm a bilingual (English and Spanish) startup veteran turned software engineer with experience across both frontend and backend development in React, JavaScript, and TypeScript. I have an eye for design and excel in collaborating with designers to bring their work to life. I have experience managing revenue generating teams of up to 50 and 9 years experience working in the e-commerce space for venture-backed companies ranging from seed stage to pre-IPO.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Après - GitHub | App | Video - React.js | TypeScript | CSS | PostgreSQL | Node.js | Express.js | RESTful API

- Designed an e-commerce shopping experience with reusable React.js components that provides a consistent and beautiful shopping experience with a fully realized brand including logo, font selection, color palette, and icons.
- Connected to an Express is, PostgreSQL, and Node is backend. Tested all routes with Postman during development.
- Created a fully responsive design that adapts to all screen sizes for ease of use regardless of the user's device.

FreshStart - GitHub | App | Video - React.js | JavaScript | CSS | MongoDB | Node.js | Express.js | RESTful API

- Built reusable React.js components for consistent design throughout the app and a mobile first flexbox design.
- Implemented JSON Web Token authorization and authentication to protect users' data on the app from being edited.
- Connected to Cloudinary's API to allow users to take photos with their mobile devices and upload them to the app.
- Ensured our team was on track to meet our deliverables with minimal merge conflicts as our team's Scrum Manager.

Cook Lore - GitHub | App | Video - React.js | JavaScript | CSS | MongoDB | Node.js | Figma | RESTful API

- Winner of General Assembly's September Sprint Hackathon. Led full stack development on a cross-functional team of developers and UX designers for General Assembly Hackathon over 3 days with the theme of accessibility.
- Translated Figma designs into a deployed web app. Met consistently with designers and led team meetings to obtain feedback on the development process. Managed version control and pull requests.
- Pair programmed with teammates across frontend and backend of the app to mentor and fix bugs.

Butter - GitHub | App | Video - JavaScript | HTML | CSS | EJS | MongoDB | Node.js | Express.js | RESTful API

- Connected to Edamam's recipe search API, used API response to render recipes and link to original recipe source.
- Built a web scraper to allow users to easily import recipe data including images by just entering the url of the recipe.
- Deployed full CRUD functionality for multiple data resources stored in MongoDB with Express is backend.
- Implemented authentication and authorization via Google OAuth preventing users from altering data they don't own.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dream Home Denver, LLC - Owner

Denver, CO 06/2020 - 11/2022

- Built two websites with WordPress to market my real estate business and generate leads for target neighborhoods
- Provided innovative solutions leading to over \$10MM in closed sales volume to date across 25 transactions
- Designed a cohesive brand identity used across all marketing channels including print, social media, and events

1stdibs - Sr. Director of Sales

New York, NY and Denver, CO 05/2017 - 04/2020

- Project managed the opening of a satellite office in Denver in two months that saved 1stdibs 20% per full time employee total cost
- Grew 1stdibs Trade annual gross merchandise value from \$50MM to \$100MM between 2017 and 2019 by increasing total number of active clients and average spend per client
- Hired both individual contributors and managers to build a team of 30 across NYC, Denver, and London offices
- Collaborated cross functionally with marketing, product, and other customer facing teams to launch industry leading trade rewards program

Homepolish - Director of Commercial Sales

New York. NY 06/2016 - 03/2017

- Implemented Salesforce.com including vetting implementation partners, creating custom objects, workflows, and dashboards to increase overall visibility into our business and empower employees across business units
- Built sales team and process from the ground up with a 65% close rate on identified opportunities
- Led forecasting and goal setting for 2017 across all business units by analyzing historical sales data

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Remote 2023

Certificate, Software Engineering

University of Miami

Bachelor of Science in Communication - Cum Laude